i'm back did you miss me that's right
you know what time it is we're back on
the hermitcraft server doing hermitcraft
things barely being able to fly and it
is time to get some work done i've been
absent on the hermitcraft server
for quite a while now and to be honest
with you
not a lot's changed from what i can see
in fact the back of the mansion
is still not done can you believe it the
fairies have not come along
and finished the mansion but you know
what
we're gonna do it we're at least gonna
cover up the hole we might not detail it
and hello
look at this shulkery christmas looking
it's like finding a five pound note in
your pocket these are very valuable
blocks that i definitely need to finish
the upside down mansion with and even
this isn't too bad so what are we going
to do in today's episode besides fix
this hole i don't know yet well first we
better catch up on everything we've
missed
uh well i didn't miss that and i
certainly didn't miss that you leave
minecraft for a couple of days
and you forget how to fly ren says are
you okay
just my dignity
well it's not an episode of hermit craft
unless you die to some very very soft
landing i don't know why that happens
but it definitely does so i've been
doing some thinking which is always
dangerous no matter what you're thinking
about and it's to do with the inside of
the base
i feel like this is such a wasted
opportunity and i keep saying yeah i'm
gonna make more farms in here and then i
simply don't
so i've been thinking
well one we actually cover this up
and we get rid of the whole the draft
that's causing my my electric bills in
my mansion to go up and i've learned
through many uses
that my current portal was a terrible
terrible idea we all have terrible ideas
sometimes it's okay like a simpsons
marathon non-stop or building a giant
hole to put a portal in now on its own
the portal's not really a problem it's
fine it's a little bit encumbersome you
have to fly up there the issue is when
you die
and when you're dead and you have no
elytra
guess what
you fall down here
and you get stuck in a pit that you
designed it's the most embarrassing
thing ever we're gonna change this i
don't know what we'll do with this
little area here hopefully finish it but
then we'll move the portal actually
inside the mansion once we make some
interior see this is why thinking's
dangerous it gives you more work but at
the moment i feel like i've got about 10
projects and none of them are done so
what we're going to do is focus on one
thing at a time and the one thing that's
nearly done
is the upside down mansion
in the nether so let's ferry over all of
these shulker boxes of materials ready
to complete
the final part of the mansion here we
are in the upside down and it doesn't
look like a whole lot has changed
except that oh my goodness
it looks like someone's arriving and
also this who's built this is this
another bdubs house
just in a different color mumbo house
party volume must be 100
100 volume
what just happened
i mean i saw this thing
maybe it already been activated before i
got there well that would mean we have
one
two
three people in the upside down
which is amazing and it looks like my
rules have been evaporated by probably a
ghast okay i fixed it do not afk and all
new citizens must be pranked mumbo kind
of came in and pranked us so i don't
know
how
did we lose
that means that
we have two people that need to be
pranked one mumbo and two i'm assuming
that was scar seeing as that was his
drill bit so
maybe i should team up with b dubs and
we're gonna figure out how we can prank
scar as a bit of a introduction to the
upside down and then he would then be
welcome to put his rule here and then i
guess b-dubs is b-dubs welcome to put
his rule here as well so
let's
get this
once and for all at least the exterior
finished and then we can call the upside
down mansion
completely done and then we'll figure
out the rest of this later on
let's go
[Music]
there we go
all completed the upside down mansion is
done except for that small hole that was
aghast
i think this has been absolutely
magnificent i got it done at tip top
speed it took i think a grand total of
five or six episodes
and building upside down
never again
not doing it no not if he paid me a
million diamonds i'd i'd never do this
again this is the the one and only build
i'm doing but the interior
does need doing
check it
check it out
oh i still haven't got rid of the farm
so they're just falling down there so
this is what's happening the pig men are
falling down and then the pig the
piglins are picking up the gold
they just they run up and they just take
it all so my gold farm is just being
eaten
by the pigs
this is the least efficient farm in the
world
and while i was actually building the
upside down finishing it off the most
disastrous thing happened
i fell in lava and i didn't have elytra
it had nothing on me and i lost loads of
stuff but anyway that's why we have
netherright gear
i might in fact ask bdubs if he can uh
do some interior with me i think he's
he's on oh no he's he right there he's
right there doing
what is he doing
making a mess
let's where did he go
i turned around oh
maybe i didn't see him but
okay that was weird let me just message
him and see if he wants to have a quick
chat let's let's pop ourselves straight
in front of him
discord
look at his eyes
oh yo
no
i wasn't ready i took my hands off the
keyboard at the wrong time what a great
kill there was holy cow i wasn't
expecting that um i i wanted to ask if
uh what your plan is for the upside down
really because i was just uh i've
literally just finished the upside down
mansion or at least the outside of it
oh yeah wanted to know what your plans
were
because
i was wondering whether you wanted to
kind of go help me with mine we got the
inside of here it's a colossal project
for an interior wow i reckon i reckon we
could like band together have you know
bedroom bedrooms and stuff you know
real you're inviting me to live in your
house with you i mean mainly because i
really want the help and i hate doing
interiors
oh i love doing interiors i would love
that
the main feature of this mansion is that
it's got a it's got it's got a farm that
leads to nowhere that's beautiful i
would love to help with interior though
that'd be amazing yeah it yeah yeah by
the way have you noticed that uh we have
another visitor out here yeah i did i
saw over yonder somewhere that
i don't know i don't know why he's done
it but he's like over there somewhere
and he's drilled through the ceiling
scar has arrived and and i don't know if
you remember or not but you set up a
little bit of a rule
of uh pranking is he on now he's not
online right now let's go and have a
little look see what we can okay see
what we're what there is to prank
because we might have to wait a while
right he was on earlier right and he was
dying
non-stop
he just yes he kind of yeah he pranks
himself a lot yeah he doesn't need our
help he was he was literally just dying
why not he died to a magma cube i mean
like how do you die to a magma cube he
managed he pulled it off did you see
that look at jelly upside down upside
down
i mean do you have any instant ideas
that pop to mind right away i have an
idea but i have i don't know if it will
work
i i don't know a lot about the nether
mechanics but i think i have an idea can
we can we do a quick test right now yes
yes i'd love to okay okay okay finally
my idea involves the respawn anchor it's
slightly different to a minecraft bed in
the fact that it's just a block i'm
wondering because he's literally been
dying over and over and over again can
we get scar stuck in an infinite death
loop oh he's good at those yeah i mean
he's he's like stuck in what his
minecraft experience is um
it's a constant death loop
but i really i'm not sure how this works
so if you right-click that
the respawn anchor
set yeah
yes okay so if i if
i kill you
oh good my goodness
i
prank
okay
right theory spawn
yes
okay okay okay no we can
test number three test number three so
okay you
did spawn on this block here okay so
yeah
now let's try this again
wow okay
perfect okay right we can do this listen
listen up listen up we use a bit of
redstone yeah we get a piston
to whenever scar spawns all we need him
to do is right click that respawn anchor
okay
once he's just one time what just once
once he's done that
we can put whatever death method we want
underneath him and then every time he
spawns in
we
the the block will retract and he will
fall to his death he will respawn the
block will retract and he will fall to
his death over and over again we just
need to be there this block right here
that block right there we just need to
keep it charged up with glowstone oh my
goodness
i love this idea the thing that kills me
the most in this game is the piglens and
the the hoglands you know the giant pigs
that thing that attacked me earlier oh
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah we make it wait
you want to have him die to those we
have a pig pit he respawns and he falls
in and then we'll we'll just stay there
for a while we'll see how long it takes
but you so that would mean we would need
to collect a bunch of those yeah or just
one no or a lot well i mean we don't
want him to get the chance to escape i i
reckon we we get a full a full pit oh no
oh boy okay
all right i've only got one of these by
the way so if um if we
don't right click it once we set it up
otherwise we're
we're in the infinite pig loop as well
yeah we don't want to do that okay
that's the worst joke i ever heard
[Laughter]
so what we do
is we tell him or we leave a sign saying
magic respawn anchor because we've seen
him die so many times yes we are great
friends here we go we are great yeah and
i mean this is like very easy as a prank
we we dig a hole and we fill yeah we
fill it with pigs all right and you
think not not one pig oh yeah
many pigs
okay
oh goodness okay here i go
i made it i'm over here
i don't know
i feel like that was a really cool fly
trick that people don't know about
uh let's go get some pigs there we go
there's one hoglands
hogland okay okay you found one guys i
forgot the fungus oh they're all peters
i need gold what where i need gold only
you'll like 20 more of these and we'll
be done
20. we pop him in the hole oh no he he
too big okay okay
he thick yeah he thick got a bit too
much pork belly you know what i mean oh
we got it we got to rename them we got
to rename them i've got some i got name
tags okay oh yeah we can silence them as
well i'm ready i'm ready here they are
uh no i felt it
no i don't i don't have the hearts for
this b-dubs this is okay this is way
harder than i thought it would be i i
kind of i kind of underestimated this
and this fungus stick does nothing i
clearly do something i clearly got that
wrong rename first yeah i'm going to
rename them
okay
all right
careful you're in it oh come on out come
on out
[Music]
oh
it's hard to count
that's not nearly if we've been doing
this for like half an hour we've only
got like six
there we go
oh my god okay that's uh that's it
that's all of them i'm renaming the big
ones there we go i got him i'll take
okay perfect
i'm playing a dangerous game i got half
a heart
no no no do it do i aggro
not them
[Music]
you fell in oh no
grief it's so easy to fall in
oh no this is the worst thing that could
have possibly happened this is this is
the limit of my oh no
he's it he's here oh my god the time
okay okay okay okay i've done i've done
it literally it's just a lever
it's done uh what was here
anvil
yes yes and bill was there yeah and then
we just
cover it up i think that's it right
because there was a yeah
and then what then what we just keep
we just
wait we're in it for the long game right
okay
this isn't very homey no no we might we
could we can make it homey i do you see
his i don't think he's at the upside
down um
left you a respawn anchor at your nether
base
oh perfect okay
so i mean this i didn't really think
this through
we need we this kind of banks on scar
dying and like we could be here several
long days
yeah yeah but also we could be here
several seconds i think maybe we use you
see when we're on we're playing is oh
scar died from fall there's a scar died
from a panda killer yeah
he dies like every every few minutes but
he hasn't even come in here to right
click the spawn anchor yet
yes so we need
he said he said thank you thank you g
he's on his way so good the plan is
simple we wait for him to hit the
respawn you know i didn't think this
plan through i thought this was flawless
and brilliant what i didn't anticipate
is the amount of waiting and chance that
we have to do because we can't leave the
lever we can't no we have to stay right
by the lever yes
it's come to this this kid is coming to
this
how fast can you break bedrock oh wait
hey hey green
he's here he's opening chest
come on wait wait we need to listen up
listen up for the dings
yeah oh sure enough that was it it
doesn't make a noise
yes he's in okay we're on the game is on
oh
sucker okay now we wait possibly the
longest time for him to perish in some
way shape or form
yes or he could
walk right off the cliff into the lava
out of here the question i want to ask
now is like what are the odds that he's
actually gonna die in the next i don't
know five seconds probably pretty low
over under i say within a minute no no
way
yeah
not a chance
we're gonna we're pro we'll be here
well
he's been on he's been to be fair he's
been online for a really long time now
and he has not died
right so yeah this is a pretty big
gamble but he was he was oh you are
joking oh he died he died okay okay okay
okay okay
wait for his name
wait for it
yes
tell me when tell me when
okay i'm waiting tell me when
it's there now just down
here
oh right right right i will i will i
will okay okay i did it
wait tell me again tell me when tell me
when okay okay
okay
oh this is working perfectly and again
again again again okay okay we've got
him now he's in he's done
yes yes again
oh yes
we should again
down he goes
[Music]
oh
oh look at this look at this smart guy
how did he hack no no no none of that
down you go
[Laughter]
[Music]
yes
this is magical
okay okay okay wait wait wait wait wait
just let's let's ask him to come on
discord
oh
oh that hurts so much i'm gonna kill you
guys i'm gonna poke those eyes
i'm gonna stop it
[Music]
down again here green let me flick the
lever a couple of times you can walk
oh this is wonderful
no
i don't even know what these creatures
are what do they have
what are their mohawks
i'm so sorry this is your initiation
into the upside down
oh my god it burns
it burns
again
it's it's gotten to the point where
tango's got his camera account on so we
can see what's going on
[Laughter]
why are the why are the pigs so mean
oh he's back go oh go okay down no no
you've got a lever you've got a control
room dude you don't know how long we've
been waiting this prank has been six
hours in the making
i've died double those hours wait you
blocked my door
no you can't get me look i'm not gonna
fall
dang it dad
when do you think enough is enough i'm
not sure oh scar i'm so sorry
don't even don't do it don't do it don't
do it green i wait for your for your
command don't do it no
it's instant it's instant death it's not
even funny it's just instant death no
scott scott
well that was your initiation
the rule have you read the rules of the
upside down i did
i really did that i'm trying to remember
what they were all citizens must be
pranked
and oh i did read that that was your
initiation
congratulations do you know what the
funniest thing is we were literally we
were hiding behind this wall
literally like we were hiding behind
this wall and you we heard you activate
the respawn anchor and we were like so
what are the uh what are the chances he
dies within like the first minute it's
not gonna happen we're gonna be waiting
here a long time dude you died in like
30 seconds
that was faint
i stopped recording i flew out and i
looked at my phone and i flew into one
of those lava streams and and
i was trying to get my potion and then i
thought i was safe and then i flew away
but i clipped a tree the chat
is insane
no
sky you don't know what you've done
okay you are officially i i hold on i
just like knight you either side you are
officially initiated into the upside
down and that means the next person to
come along
we all need to band together and then
prank them although i'm not sure how we
top this and i'm definitely not spending
another six hours on this this was
ridiculous
no maybe we just get some weapons and
slice them up
that prank actually took so long that it
was about 2 a.m before i actually got to
bed i was obviously working with b-dubs
who was on the other side of the planet
to me so
time zone's fun it was a bit messy once
we got there it was a bit messy
but we actually made it through
and it worked it could have been cleaner
admittedly it could have been cleaner
but it worked to a certain degree so now
that the exterior of the upside down
mansion is done and b dubs is actually
interested on doing the interior with me
i think it's safe to say
we can actually get started on this bit
of the inside it's been such a long time
since i've done interior
whoa
what
oh my goodness
these guys are just storage
i might have just found something here i
can let these guys fall
because if i hold on has this guy got
loads of golden golden little trinkets
on him he has he's just holding stacks
of gold they've been
the piglins have been picking up the
gold and i knew that and i thought they
just vanished but they didn't they
literally stand down here collecting if
i don't even need any chests or hoppers
or anything the piglens can just pick it
up for me that is amazing
unintentional
very inefficient gold farm we're gonna
move this but that that is an accidental
farm right there so my plan is to get
this nicely mob proofed because i mean
look at this there's just things
spawning everywhere it's affecting my
rates it's not good and it's not clean
for what we want to do here in the
interior
i've just thought of something i've just
thought of something really really fun
so we have to make obviously a tunnel
all the way back to spawn we've got one
but you have to fly through it so i'm
thinking a punishment for breaking the
rules could be tunnel duty you've got to
you've got to help make
the tunnel back so it would involve
placing a lot of glass glass
this isn't glass compressed ice so that
we can make a faster way using boats and
not using up all of our fireworks
whenever we do this so
i think we could we could i think we
could easily introduce tunnel duty into
this thing
seeing as it took about an hour to make
this tunnel in the first place this is
not a fun punishment and then tunnel
duty couldn't also include further down
the line making this look a bit prettier
decorating the sides and such speaking
of which
we need to head back to the shopping
district
uh-oh
the tunnel has been
someone's drilled right through the
tunnel
oh no
scar
he must have not seen this at all
hey scott you're on tunnel duty already
let's check
two out of three sold and a hole in
scar's face over there not bad not bad
at all i can't actually remember which
order i put this in so what was left ah
the naf barge box
that's what was left
unfortunate unfortunate the naf barge
box is going to go back into the system
at the end of the episode i'm gonna make
three more boxes as well two more boxes
and we'll put them in again and we'll
see if people like them even more
we want to make it worth it but it looks
like i've got some stocking up to do at
some point
adding to our quite substantial diamond
pile now
we are going to fill this up
but the real reason that we're here
oh i forgot about the mycelium
resistance
it's gone we need we need we need what
you can't stop the mycelium resistance
it must it has to start small that's i'm
making up my own rules for this but the
mycelium resistance has to start small
i don't really know what's going on here
here's another spot but we could do this
what is mycelium
what what is it it's like purple and it
has particles on it and stuff
it kind of is it a fungus of some kind
fungal resistance
we shall reclaim this land okay we've
got two spots you can't stop the
resistance anyway the real reason that
we're in the shopping district right now
is because i wanted to try out iskall's
treasure island game there's a there's a
lot of new stuff that he sort of told
everyone about so i want to take a look
and i want a piece of the pie last time
this game was sold out before i could
really get a good go at it so
we're gonna we're gonna play again i
obviously need to read up on this thing
so if you're not aware he has dug a lot
of treasure in a distant island and you
have the opportunity to dig it up
purchase a treasure spoon to the left
for 32 whoa that's a lot of money and
head out to the island to try your luck
you may only dig using the treasure
spoon you may only break blocks that the
spoon is meant to break and no cheese
all treasure is very valuable
wow wow wow
looks like people have been buying a lot
of spoons okay so it's
diamonds how many diamonds have we got
we're gonna roll the dice i might need
to take some funds out of the barge for
this
okay we're buying
six
spoons
that should be enough to make sure we at
least get one prize
they're all different durabilities
this i got a shortchanged on this one
so okay some are better than others i
wasn't expecting that i was expecting
like wooden shovels
and then over here you can buy a clue or
two
the chances are people have already dug
around these places we'll buy two clues
and let's see what we got don't let the
stone
don't let stone scare you off and where
the dunes don't end
minus
1700 that's a long way away
aha this looks like the one
okay now how have people done this
they've just dug straight down by the
looks of things so don't let stone scare
you off
let's start here so we'll go straight
down i hope he hasn't put lava in this
okay
i don't i don't think i've done this
very sensibly have i
okay we might need to reassess how we
play this game
i've just wasted 62 diamonds
doing rubbish okay so we go down
let's go down
oh we can go pretty deep here
oh come on
this isn't good
this is not good uh let's try here
no
so we can go one two and then down i've
got a system now
but it's um
it's not gone well folk it's not gone
well at all
one two let's go here
go straight down no
just one would be nice
one one would do
one one chest would do
no
i have rolled the dice
and i have lost
i okay so i wasted loads
digging badly
over here
and there's probably already been
someone gone okay i feel like we can't
leave it like that i feel rotten
i feel rotten i feel
i i wasn't expecting to hit nothing no i
don't think we can leave it like that
we're going to try again it's a good job
that the barge has been so successful so
i can waste all my money
on iskall's game
right
we're going for another another five
spoons right round two
round two don't let stone scare you off
so let's try this one here
really
nothing
okay let's try this side
i've used three shovels already
this is unbelievable
iska what have you done
i haven't let stone scare me off and yet
and yet i'm finding absolutely nothing
these points of interest are duds
no
[Music]
oh
that wasn't my fault
we are in trouble we can good
good oh
come on
i'll tell i'll tell this girl that
there's uh there's been a couple of
hiccups okay we're going big
we're going big we're spending all our
profits being an idiot
this is what it's all about this is what
this is what the bar just been about the
whole time
being a fool
buying gold shovels i'll tell you what
if this isn't worth it i'm gonna be so
annoyed iskall you better have a good
prize here right two
four
six
eight
one
all right we got our shovels we're going
back
i just know that there's gonna be a lot
of you that are seriously angry that
i've spent the barge profits on this
game but
it might be worth it it literally it
might be worth it i'm not sure but we're
gonna try
because i have checked and the rewards
for this game are massive
i still feel obliged to try the big rock
what about by the bed
anything by the bed
oh
this has gone very deep
this is like surprise surprisingly low
down
there's got to be something
now do i keep going cause this this is
really deep down
i don't know if the game is meant to do
this
i'm literally so deep now that i i don't
know if the game is meant to be this
deep
i am forced to conclude that this is a
dead end dud
and my goodness was a major dud iscal
has kindly delivered some more golden
shovels because uh the machine ran out
so i didn't actually get what i paid for
but we're back can you go through can
you go through here
get can you just crawl in spaces as well
i'm guessing iskall's kind of done his
best to hide them if the jackpots are
that good
is that one
yes
oh no
oh no that's one free dig
okay these aren't as omega as i thought
they were
oh no
that's one dig that's rough
that's very how do i get out of here as
well
oh no
i'm definitely not gonna get my money
back and i'm stuck in here forever i
think i've wasted a lot of a lot of
diamonds
a lot of diamonds down the drain
this is not very good why don't we
continue this one
straight down
oh yo
ah again
gold blocks
i thought we were gonna get diamonds
galore here okay
so we got two
i thought these things were full of
netherite and diamonds and
goodies for everyone
okay we actually do have some more
spoons
we got one shovel left and i think i
think we're gonna have to face the fact
that we've we have either been very
unlucky or iskall has created the
biggest money maker ever because 32
diamonds oh man i didn't even make my
money back on that single dig there's
just there's far too many options and
not nearly enough barrels by the looks
of things
what i want to know is what where the
dunes don't end means where the dunes
don't end well sand dunes are like you
know big wavy piles of sand
and they all seem to end
one way or another unless it means
straight down from here
which it doesn't i think we're about to
lose
um
okay
the bad news is i i don't have any good
news but the bad news is we lost a lot
of money we lost a lot of diamonds i'm
never playing this game again it is
um
not good
not good i worked systematically i tried
the points of interest
and we won
a lot of gold which is free
soon because i'm making a gold farm
oh this is not good well i think that's
probably where we're going to have to
and unfortunately
end this episode
leaving me feeling a little bit
scratching my head wondering what i'm
gonna do i think next episode i've got
to go
make my money back somehow
i don't even know how
oh i feel so i feel devastated
absolutely devastated that must have
been the most unlucky run
ever
so iskall took probably
nine stacks of diamonds from me and i
got 32 diamonds and a whole lot of gold
from two barrels
not good
there was one of my clues that i just
don't understand and then i followed
this clue and it didn't get me anywhere
bad luck
um we're probably gonna have to come up
with our own money-making scheme for the
next episode
but thank you very much for watching and
i shall see you in the next episode
please help me out how do we make
diamonds very quickly i
devastated i worked so hard on the barge
money and then i just i just wasted it
all
i'm embarrassed
i'm so embarrassed this is what happens
in hermitcraft you work hard oh man no
okay okay i'm just gonna go and cry